Vice President for Business, Property Manager Records, including Branch Campus Site Studies 1968-1991
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Vice President for Business, Property Manager Records, including Branch Campus Site Studies
1968-1991
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 246
4.5 linear feet 5 containers
Property and siting records consist of reports, projects, memos, correspondence, pictures, and newspaper articles.
Organizational History:
The Vice-President for Business is responsible for oversight of a wide variety of administrative matters at the university, including properties and physical facilities. The office includes a property manger among its staff.
Property and siting records consist of reports, projects, memos, correspondence, pictures, and newspaper articles. These make up two record series. The first concern the sites for branch campuses. The second concerned the acquisition and management of property by the university. Many of these properties are adjacent or near the central campus at Pullman.
A large portion of the records are committee records from building and locating commmittees. These files are inclusive of copies of many documents. The original and primary copies of these are maintained in the records of the Office of Facilities Development.
The Collection is open for research use.
Property records, and including branch campus property and siting records, were were transferred to the Washington State University's Libraries in 1993 (UA93-08) the Vice President for Business.
Washington State University. Vice President for Business--Archives; Washington State University. Vice President for Business--Records and correspondence; Washington State University at Spokane--History--Records and correspondence; Washington State University at Tri-Cities--History--Records and correspondence; Washington State University at Vancouver--History--Records and correspondence
Universities and colleges--Business management--Washington (State)--Pullman--Archives
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- WSU Spokane
  - Environmental reports (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Higher Education Coordinating Board, correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - HECB, study (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Spokane Intercollegiate Research and Technology Institute #1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Spokane Intercollegiate Research and Technology Institute #2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Capital budget request (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Operating cost (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Land negotiations (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Appraisal report (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General correspondence (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Maps and photos (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meetings' minutes and handouts (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - City and university district (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Academic program (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Eastern Washington University building (Box 1, Folder 15)
- WSU Tri Cities
  - Site selection, ad hoc committee (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Site selection, general correspondence and reports, 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Site selection, general correspondence and reports, 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Advisory council (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Donated property (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Land acceptance and HECB correspondence (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Project costs (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - McKinley architects, correspondence (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Benton county property tax (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - University center, 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - University center, 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - General correspondence, 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - General correspondence, 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- WSU Vancouver
  - General acquisition information, correspondence and reports (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Board of Regents, correspondence (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Burke and Lee, architects (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Letters of support and concern (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Consultation selection (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - General correspondence (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Environmental impact statements (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Environmental issues (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Facilities planning, 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Facilities planning, 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - "Options" (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - HECB (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Phase I development (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Project costs (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - "Mays property" (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Plamodon property (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Salmon Creek Land Company (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Property questions and correspondence (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Selection process report, 1 May 90 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Site recommendation committee report (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Environmental impact statement, 17 July 90 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Comprehensive physical plant (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Growth Management Act (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Supplemental site reports, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Newspaper articles (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Site selection, miscellaneous reports and memos (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - City of Vancouver proposal for WSU branch campus (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Interim planning report, 20 Sep 89 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Phase I report, 22 Jun 90 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Supplemental site report, 3 Aug 90 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Supplemental site report, 30 Aug 90 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - City reports and findings (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Minutes (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence from Zimmer, Gunsul, Frasca partnership (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - "Jay's working papers" (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Miscellaneous site selection correspondence (Box 4, Folder 64)
- WSU Properties
  - Adams school, 1976-1989 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Bonney Lake (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - N.E. 640 Morton, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Burger King (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Camp Roger Larson (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - 1502 Reaney Way, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Columbia River Orchards Foundation (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Glacier Park (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Little Goose Reservoir, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Meske, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1987 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Mt. Vernon, 1970-1988 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - 503 Hill, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - North-South ski bowl (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Off campus warehouse (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Potter house (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Rolling Hills development, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - 660 Gray Land, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - 513 Morton, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Smoot Hill management, 1968-1986 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Oregon property, #1 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Oregon property, #2 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Trillium apartments (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Wackman property, 1968-1979 (Box 5, Folder 88)